Simon Flexner Papers 1891-1946 Mss.B.F365
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Simon Flexner Papers, 1891-1946; 115.5 linear feet
  - Dalen, Albin
  - Daley, Charles M.
  - Daly, Thomas F.
  - Dalton, A. J.
  - Dalton, Charles F.
  - D'Amico, Alfred J.
  - Damkohler, Helen M.
  - Damon, H. H.
  - Damrosch, Mrs. Frank
  - Dana, Charles L.
  - Dana, Edward S.
  - Danchakoff, Vera
  - Dandy, Walter E.
  - Dane, Carle H.
  - Danforth, R. S.
  - Daniels, Frederick L.
  - Daniels, Josephus
  - Daniels, Worth B.
  - Danilevsky, V. J.
  - D'Antonio, M. J.
  - DaPorte, Joseph V.
  - Darby, Albert
  - Darby, R. N. Gordon
  - Darcy, Edith
  - Dare, E. M.
  - Darling, Samuel T.
  - Darlington, Thomas
  - Darnall, C. R.
  - Darrach, L. W.
  - Darrach, William D.
  - Dashiel, L. M.
  - Daubney, R.
  - Daufresne, Maurice
  - D'Aunoy, Rigney
  - Davenport, Charles Benedict, 1914-1940; ca. 40 items
    Includes: Correspondence concerning Heren's attack on his research at Eugenics Record Office, 1913-14. Letter to W. H. Welch outlining plans for future of Eugenics Record Office and estimate of funds required for its operation. (Davenport hoped that Rockefeller Foundation would defray costs not covered by endowment from Mrs. Harriman), 1/5/15 (copy). Letter to SF about traits of persons not accepted for military service, 12/19/22. Correspondence on SF's biography of W. H. Welch.
  - Davenport, Frederick M.
  - Davenport, Russell W.
  - Davidoff, Leo M.
  - Davidson, David
  - Davidson, Frida
  - Davidson, G. H.
  - Davidson, Gabriel
  - Davidson, Percy B.
  - Davies, C. E.
  - Davies, Stanley P.
  - Davis, Addison D.
  - Davis, Allan
  - Davis, Charles Henry
  - Davis, David J.
  - Davis, David M.
  - Davis, E. Mildred
  - Davis, Edward A.
  - Davis, Edith H.
  - Davis, Grace
  - Davis, Gwilym G.
  - Davis, Helen I.
  - Davis, J. J.
  - Davis, J. P.
  - Davis, John A.
  - Davis, John Staige
  - Davis, John W.
  - Davis, Katharine B.
  - Davis, N. W.
  - Davis, Norman H.
  - Davis, R. H.
  - Davis, Robert C.
  - Davis, S. G.
  - Davis, Samuel M.
  - Davis, Thomas K.
  - Davis, V. G.
  - Davis, Watson
  - Davis, Willa Fricke
  - Davis, W. M.
  - Davison, H. P.
  - Davison, Roland
  - Davison, Wilbur C., 3 folders
  - Daviss, E. P.
  - Davisson, C. J., 2 folders
  - Davney, M. Y.
  - Dawes, Rufus
  - Dawson, M. H.
  - Dawson, Wilburt C.
  - Day, Alex A.
  - Day, Arthur L.
  - Day, Frank L.
  - Day, George Parmly
  - Day, John M.
  - Day, Jonathan C.
  - Day, Marion L.
  - Daykin, Frances
  - Dayton, Arthur B.
  - Dean, Bashford
  - Dean, H. R.
  - Dean, L. W.
  - Dean, Nora D.
  - Dean, Rollin C.
  - Deane, H. T.
  - Deardurff, Cora
  - Dearing, R. M.
  - Deaver, John B.
  - DeBaum, Lewis H.
  - Debevoise, Thomas M., 2 folders
  - DeBilles, Edouard
  - DeBlasi, D.
  - Debove, M.
  - Debuchi, Katsuji
  - DeCamp, Joseph
  - Decker, Harry Eyerson
  - Declich, Melchiore
  - Decker, C. J.
  - Dederer, Carleton
  - Deeds, Helen
  - Deeks, William E.
  - Defandorf, James H.
  - de Fontnouvelle, Ch.
  - DeFord, William A.
  - DeForest, Calvert M.
  - DeForest, Henry P.
  - DeForest, Nora Blatch
  - DeForest, Robert W.
  - Defries, H. D.
  - Defries, Robert D., 1923-1932; 33 items
    Includes: Correspondence on the supply of insulin from Toronto to HIM.
  - "Pathogenicity of a fixed Strain of Rabies Virus for white mice''
  - DeFritsch, Hugo G.
  - Deglowitz, Rudolf
  - DeHaas, Fannie W.
  - DeHaas, Jacob
  - DeHaas, T. W.
  - Dehelly, Georges
  - Deichmann, O. H.
  - Deichmiller, Conrad
  - DeJongh, Juan J.
  - DeKock, Gilles
  - DeKruif, Paul H., 1920-1922; 3 folders
    Includes: Administrative materials relating to his work at RIMR, 1920-1922. Drafts of articles for Century Magazine and the volume Civilization in the United States -- an Inquiry by Thirty Americans Medicine, 1922.
  - DeLana, John C.
  - Deland, Margaret
  - Delafield, Charlotte H.
  - DeLaguna, Grace A.
  - Delaney, Martin D.
  - Delano, F. M.
  - Delano, Frederic A.
  - Delano, Jane A.
  - Delano, William Adams
  - Delatour, H. Beckman
  - Delavan, D. B.
  - DeLazlo, Henry
  - Delepine, Sheridan
  - DeLima, Agnes
  - DeLisle, Agnes
  - Deller, Edwin
  - Delphey, Eden V.
  - Demarest, John M.
  - Demarest, W. C., 3 folders
  - Demerson, G.
  - Deming, Clinton D.
  - Deming, H. G.
  - Deming, Julia
  - Dench, E. B.
  - Denderick, William H.
  - Denison, A. B.
  - Dennis, Charles C.
  - Dennis, Frederic S.
  - Dennis, L. M.
  - Denno, W. J.
  - Denton, James Way
  - Denton M. F.
  - Denys, I.
  - Denys, Joseph
  - DeOgny, P. A.
  - DePew, Evartz V.
  - DePorte, Joseph V.
  - Derby, Richard
  - Dercle, D.
  - Dercum, Francis X.
  - DeSchweinitz, G. E.
  - DeSchweinitz, Karl
  - Desrosiers, Horace
  - Deutsch, Bernard S.
  - DeValin, C. M.
  - Devine, Edward T.
  - Dewey, Bradley
  - Dewey, Davis R.
  - Dewey, Frederick
  - Dewey, John
  - Dewey, Thomas E.
  - DeWitt, Wallace
  - Dexter, T. H.
  - Deznai, Victor
  - Diamond, Philip
  - Dibble, S. E.
  - Dibbs, A. G.
  - Dibert, Florence M.
  - Dichter, Charles L.
  - Dick, George F.
  - Dick, L. J.
  - Dickey, Frank A., 2 folders
  - Dickie, W. M.
  - Dickinson, M. D.
  - Dickinson, Robert L.
  - Dickinson, W. Giford
  - Dickson, A. J.
  - Dickson, Ernest C.
  - Dickson, J. A.
  - Dickson, W. E. Carnegie
  - Diefendorf, Allen Ross
  - Dielman, Mrs. Ernest
  - Diem, Oscar
  - Dienaide, Francis R.
  - Diener, A. L.
  - Dienes, Louis
  - Dieterich, Frederick H.
  - Dietrich, A.
  - Digby, Kenelm H.
  - Dight, Herman H.
  - Dillehunt, Richard B.
  - Dillingham, Frederick H.
  - Dillon, Joseph A.
  - Diller, Theodore
  - Dimont, Julius
  - Dingman, John C.
  - Dings, E. Martin
  - Dinkelspeil, Ike
  - Dinner Club
  - Dintjis, Mrs. S.
  - Di Santo, Nicola
  - Dittus, C.
  - Diveley, Rex L.
  - Diven, John
  - Diver, Mrs. H.
  - Dix, C. W.
  - Dix, Dorothy
  - Dixon, Archibald
  - Dixon, John
  - Dixon, Samuel G.
  - Dixon, W. E.
  - Doan, Charles A.
  - Doan, Joseph C
  - Doane, Eugene
  - Doane, J. M.
  - Dobie, D. Robertson
  - Dobson, A. T.
  - Dobson, John M.
  - Dochez, Alphonse Raymond, 1917-1935; 4 folders
    Includes: Correspondence about his work in Texas on pneumococcus as assistant to Rufus I. Cole, 1917. General correspondence on Dochez' work with tuberculosis.
  - Dock, George
  - Dodd, E. M.
  - Dodd, Frank C.
  - Dodd, William E.
  - Dodd, William S.
  - Dodds, Thomas Garfield
  - Dodge, A. H.
  - Dodge, Bayard
  - Dodge, Ceveland H.
  - Dodge, Edith
  - Dodson, Austin I.
  - Dodson, John M.
  - Doerr, Robert
  - Doheny, Robert
  - Dohme, A. R.
  - Dohring, Albert C.
  - Dolbey, Robert
  - Dold, H.
  - Dole, Malcolm
  - Dolley, D. H.
  - Dominguez, A. G.
  - Donahue, F. W.
  - Donald, William
  - Donaldson, Henry Herbert, 1917-1926; 20 items
    Includes: Correspondence about an antivivisection bill in California state legislature, 1920. Letters concerning meetings of NAS, and on Richard M. Pearce's election to APS, 1914.
  - Donaldson, W.
  - Donham, Wallace B.
  - Donnan, F. G.
  - Donnell, Lucy W.
  - Donnelly, James J.
  - Donnelly, L. T.
  - Donnelly, Lucy M.
  - Donner, Vywyan
  - Donogan, J. F.
  - Donovan, Florence T.
  - Donovan, Joseph P.
  - Donovan, M. E.
  - Donovan, P. J.
  - Dooley, M. S.
  - Dooman, David S.
  - Dopter, Charles
  - Doran, Catherine A.
  - Doremus, Carl
  - Dorland, III A .Newman
  - Dorman, H. F.
  - Dornan, William J.
  - Dorset, M.
  - Dorsey, H. W.
  - Dorsey, N. Ernest
  - Dorting, E. E.
  - Dosland, Max A.
  - Doty, Alvah H., 1915-1931; 5 folders
    Includes: Correspondence and reports on social poliomyelitis studies in New York City and on infantile paralysis in New Rochelle, N.Y., funded by Rockefeller Foundation and administered by RIMR.
  - Doubleday, Ida
  - Dougherty, Daniel S
  - Dougherty, Katherine
  - Douglas, A. J.
  - Douglas, Charles
  - Douglas, G. R.
  - Douglas, J. L.
  - Douglas, S. R.
  - Douglas, Walter
  - Doum, J. Henry
  - Dow, William S.
  - Dowdall, J. A.
  - Dowling, Oscar, 2 folders
  - Dowman, Charles Edward
  - Downes, W. A.
  - Downey, Hal
  - Downing, Augustus S.
  - Downing, E. D.
  - Downs, P. S.
  - Dows, David
  - Doxara, John
  - Drane, James E.
  - Draper, George, 1914-1936; 7 folders
    Includes: Correspondence on his work with poliomyelitis and with meningitis victims in U.S. army camps in the southern stated, ig.14-18. Letter attached to a report on Draper's work on botulism conducted as chief surgeon to American Expeditionary Forces in France, January, 1918. Correspondence about his medical patients, 1920-1936. [materials not organized]
  - Draper, W. D.
  - Draper, William K.
  - Dray, Madeleine D.
  - Dreiser, Theodore
  - Drennan, Jennie G.
  - Dresbach, M.
  - Drescher, William A. E.
  - Dresel, Irmgard
  - Drew, James
  - Driesch, Hans
  - Drinker, Cecil K., 1928-1932; 5 items
    Includes: General correspondence.
  - Drolet, Godias J.
  - Drought, James
  - Drury, Samuel S.
  - Dualls, Guy L.
  - Duane, Russell
  - Duane, William
  - Dublin, Louis I.
  - DuBois, Eugene Floyd, 1917-1939; 36 items
    Includes: Letters on Harold Himwich's trip to Europe; also general correspondence.
  - DuBois, Frances M.
  - DuBos, Rene Jules, 1942; 5 items
    Includes: Correspondence on the translation of his article on prevention of poliomyelitis.
  - Dubron, Mrs. Richard
  - Dudley, E. C.
  - Dudley, G. S.
  - Duesberg, Jules
  - Duffield, Henry G.
  - Duffield, Thomas J.
  - Duffield, William
  - Duffus, Robert L.
  - Duffy, James O. G.
  - Dufton, A. F.
  - Dugan, Francis D.
  - Duggan, Stephen P.
  - Duggar, B. M.
  - Dujarric de la Riviere, Rene
  - Duke, William, Jr.
  - Dulaney, Paul
  - Duncan, Charles
  - Duncan, Charles H.
  - Duncan, Edward
  - Duncan, William M.
  - Dunford, Ralph E.
  - Dunham, Carroll
  - Dunham, Edward Kellogg, 1910-1935; 3 folders
    Includes: Correspondence on his work with meningitis victims in Armed Forces at Rhode Island, 1917. Letter discussing work of Harold Anioss on the effects of chloramines on poliomyelitis. General correspondence with Mrs. E. K. Dunham, 1922-1935.
  - Dunham, H. G.
  - Dunham, H. J.
  - Dunham, John Dudley
  - Dunham, Lawrence B.
  - Dunham, Theodore
  - Dunlap, A. M.
  - Dunn, B. Sherwood
  - Dunn, Charles Hunter, 1907-1915; ca. 30 items
    Includes: Correspondence on his work with meningitis victims in Boston; requests for antimeningitis serum to RIMR; case outline and statistics on cases treated with antimeningitis serum. Correspondence on his work with antiinfluenza serum.
  - Dunn, F. C.
  - Dunn, Gano
  - Dunn, H. A.
  - Dunn, L. H.
  - Dunn, Leslie C.
  - Dunn, Louis S.
  - Dunn, Marshall L.
  - Dunn, Robert F.
  - Dunning, M. B.
  - Du Nouy, P. Lecomte, 1919-1937; 60 items
    Includes: General correspondence on his work at RIMR, 1921. Report on X-ray crystal analysis and estimates of costs of a complete crystallography department at RIMR, 1926. Letter on Du Nouy's visit to Geophysicial Laboratory of Carnegie Institution to acquire the latest skills in X-ray crystallography. Du Nouy's description of his work at the Institut Pasteur, and information on its internal organization, 1930. Correspondence concerning the supposed accident that BCG vaccine from Institut Pasteur killed children in Lribeck, 1930; Du Nouy's explanation that the deaths could not have been so caused. List of his papers produced at Institut Pasteur, Department of Molecular Physics, 1928-1931.
  - Dunstan, J.
  - Duprat, Frank
  - Dupuy, Maurice
  - Durand, Henry
  - Durand, Jay I.
  - Durand, W. S.
  - Durant, Paul
  - Durell, E. H.
  - Durham, Mary Louise
  - Durkee, J, Stanley
  - Durrant, James A.
  - Duryea, A. W.
  - Duryea, Chester F.
  - DuToit, P. J.
  - Dutt, H. N.
  - Dutt, V. W.
  - Dutton, C. C.
  - Dutton, Laura S.
  - Duval, Charles W., 1908-1934; 6 folders
    Includes: Correspondence on his work with meningitis victims at the Montreal General Hospital, including requests for samples of Flexneris antimeningitis serum. Letter from SF informing Duval that he had been recommended for the Chair of Pathology and Bacteriology at Tulane University; and on his dissatisfaction with his position at Tulane. Letters on his application for the post at the University of Virginia vacated by Banting's acceptance of the Chair of Pathology at Wisconsin. Letters on his work with poliomyelitis at the Charity Hospital, New Orleans.
  - Duval, D. P.
  - Duval, L.
  - Dwight, H.
  - Dyer, E. T.
  - Dyer, Isadore
  - Dyer, R.E.
  - Dynan, Nicholas J.
  - Dysentery
  - Eagan, Martha
  - Eagle, Edward
  - Eagleton, Wells P.
  - Eakin, Alexander
  - Earle, Baylis H.
  - Earle, C. A.
  - Earle, H. R.
  - East, E. M.
  - Eastman, Fred W.
  - Eastman, George, 1920-1921; 13 items
    Includes: Inquiry about the work at RIMR on X-ray treatment of tonsils.
  - Eastman, Lucius R.
  - Eastman Visiting Professorship, 1936-1938; 6 folders
    Includes: Correspondence regarding arrangements for SF's trip to England, 1937-1938. Invitations to dinners and meetings etc. Memorandum by SF on the establishing of a complete school of medicine at Oxford University using Nuffield funds, its feasibility and necessary costs. General correspondence.
    - Folder 1: (A - Aydelotte, Frank)
    - Folder 2: (Aydelotte, Frank)
    - Folder 3: (Bell - Frechtling)
    - Folder 4: (Gipson - Veale)
    - Folder 5: (Misc. 1)
    - Folder 6: (Misc. 2)
  - Easton, Blanche
  - Eastwood, Arthur
  - Eaton, Ernest R.
  - Eaton, W. M.
  - Eaves, Ed
  - Ebaugh, Franklin G.
  - Ebeling, Albert Henry, 1916-1924; 11 items
  - Eberson, Frederick, 1916-1938; 6 folders
    Includes: General correspondence while Eberson was with North Manchurian Plague Prevention Service, 1917. Letters from SF assuring Eberson of a position at RIMR on his return from China; and about his working under Opie at Washington University Medical School. Letters to SF describing his work vith poliomyelitis at University of Southern California.
  - Ebright, George E.
  - Eccles, Dr.
  - Echols, Chester M.
  - Ecker, Enrique E. de
  - Eckerson, Lowell B
  - Eckmair, Frank C.
  - Eckstein, Gustav
  - Ecole Superieure d'Aeronautique et de Construction Mecanique de Lausanne (Suisse)
  - Edel, Ernst
  - Edelman, S
  - Edgar, J Clifton
  - Edinburgh Univ. Club
  - Edison, Charles
  - Edison, Thomas A.
  - Edlich, Theodore J.
  - Edmunds, C. E.
  - Edmunds, C. K.
  - Edsall, David L., 1910-1930; 3 folders
    Includes: Letters on his acceptance of Chair of Preventive Medicine at Washington University, St. Louis; and giving his reasons for resigning his position at St. Louis; and on acceptance of Chair of Medicine at Harvard. Letter asking SF to insure that Cornell consider A. E. Taylor for an opening in physiological chemistry. In the same letter, Edsall describes deficiencies at University of Pennsylvania. Edsall is confident about future of A. N. Richards as opportunities for trained pharmacologists are abundant, 3/13/11. In his reply SF expresses doubts on qualifications of Richards as a trained investigator. Correspondence about the first Dunham lecture, 1928.
  - Edwards, Charles L.
  - Edwards, Charles W.
  - Edwards, Geoffrey L.
  - Edwards, J. F.
  - Edwards, J. Graham
  - Edwards, James F.
  - Edwards, James L.
  - Edwards, W. D.
  - Edwards, Sir William
  - Egan, Martin
  - Egbert, Alice W
  - Eggers, Carl
  - Eggleston, Cary
  - Eggleston, Margery K., 1920-1935; 10 folders
    Includes: Administrative correspondence concerning applicants for positions at Peking Union Medical College; budgets, memos, minutes, etc. concerning PUMC.
  - Ehrich, William S
  - Ehrlich, Hedwig
  - Ehrlich, Paul, 4 folders
    Includes: Correspondence on his treatment of leukemia with neosalvarsan. Correspondence on exchange of cultures of bacteria and viruses between Ehrlich and RIMR. Letter on new Goldman Institute for the study of vital staining, 9/4/11, 15 pp. Correspondence on Noguchi's visit to Ehrlich's Institut, 1913. (Most letters are in German but there are many translations.); Manuscript of biography of Ehrlich by Martha Marquardt.
    - Folder 1, 1904-1912
    - Folder 2, 1912-1914
    - Folder 3, 1912-1915
    - Biographical Sketch by Martha Marquardt
  - Paul Ehrlich Foundation
  - Ehrlich, Mrs. Paul
  - Ehrlich Fund, 8 folders
    - Folder 1: (A - Billikopf)
    - Folder 2: (Billikopf - Br)
    - Folder 3: (C - I)
    - Folder 4: (J - Le)
    - Folder 5: (Li - P)
    - Folder 6: (Ra - Ri)
    - Folder 7: (Ro - Ru)
    - Folder 8: (S - Z)
  - Eichel, Otto R.
  - Eichhorn, A.
  - Eigenmann, C. H.
  - Einhorn, Max
  - Einhorn, Rosa
  - Eiseman, Henry
  - Eisendrath, Joseph N.
  - Eisenlohr, E.
  - Eisler, Samuel
  - Ekberg, H. W.
  - Elbaz, Jacob
  - Elderz, C.
  - Eldred, Byron E.
  - Eldridge, Sidney W.
  - Eldridge, Thomas Edwin
  - Eldridge, Watson W.
  - Electric Shock, 1926-1930; 33 folders
    Includes: Correspondence with members of a committee formed to study the effects of severe electric shock, and with its investigators.
    - Appleton, Charles W.
    - Auer, John
    - Bailey, Percival
    - Cannon, Walter B.
    - Carlson, Anton J
    - Carter, Edward Perkin
    - Cobb, Stanley
    - Cohn, Alfred E.
    - Conferences
    - Cowdry, E. V.
    - Drinker, Cecil K.
    - Drinker, Philip
    - Erlanger, Joseph
    - Hektoen, Ludwig
    - Howell, William H.: Folder 1
    - Howell, William H.: Folder 2
    - Jellinek, S.
    - Langworthy, Orthello R.
    - Lieb, John William: Folder 1
    - Lieb, John William: Folder 2
    - Maccallum, William G.
    - Maclachlan, Wills
    - Mallory, Frank B.
    - Norris, Charles
    - Osterhout, W. J. V.
    - Reports
    - Robertson, Albert D.
    - Scott, Charles B.
    - Sloan, M. S.
    - Smith, Frank W.
    - Smith, Frederick
    - Van Slyke, Donald D.
    - Williams, Horatio B.
  - Elgood, Mrs. Percival
  - Eli Lilly and Company
  - Eliot, Charles W.
  - Eliot, Ellswarth
  - Elizaldo, R. M.
  - Elkin, W. S.
  - Elkinton, Joseph
  - Elkus, Abram J.
  - Eller, Joseph J
  - Ellery, Edward
  - Ellicott, Nancy P., 1912-1935; 4 folders
    Includes: Administrative correspondence concerning Rockefeller Hospital.
  - Ellicott, V. L.
  - Ellingston, John, R.
  - Elliott, Charles A.
  - Elliott, Edith L.
  - Elliott, Harry
  - Elliott, James
  - Elliott, John H.
  - Elliott, Marguerite
  - Ellis, Arthur W. M., 1915-1944; 3 folders
    Includes: Requests to SF for meningitis serum. Letters on his appointment to professorship of medicine at London Hospital, 1924. Letter criticizing SF's historical account of post vaccinal encephalitis published in JAMA. Ellis states that Turnbull had observed post vaccinal encephalitis as early as 1922, which when reported led to the Ministry of Health's forming the Andrews Committee on vaccination; that Turnbull's full report to Andrews Committee had not been published because it would have had adverse effects on practice of vaccination.
  - Ellis, Don Carlos
  - Ellis, E. F.
  - Ellis, Earl
  - Ellis, Minnie B.
  - Ellis, Ralph
  - Ellsworth, James W.
  - Ellwood, Charles A.
  - Elman, Robert
  - Elmer, Walter G.
  - Elsberg, Charles A.
  - Elser, William J.
  - Elsmith, Dorothy
  - Elsner, Henry L.
  - Elton, Charles
  - Elvesser, Leo
  - Elwood, Everett S.
  - Ely, C. F.
  - Ely, Frances A.
  - Ely, Frank A.
  - Ely, Gertrude
  - Ely, Robert E.
  - Embree, Edwin Rogers, 1917-1936; 24 folders
    Includes: Letter expressing concern that the press charged Rockefeller Foundation dominated certain departments of New York City administration, 9/22/17. Announcement to SF of meetings of Rockefeller Trustees to discuss constitution of the Foundation, 1917. Letters from Embree informing SF that Rockefeller Foundation would fund part of the expenses of N. Y. Committee of After Care of Infantile Paralysis cases. Minutes of Executive Committee Meeting of Rockefeller Foundation on tuberculosis research in France, 4/28/17. Report of Charles H. W. Foster on work of Rockefeller Foundation War Relief Commission, Berne, Switzerland. Notice of meetings of Executive Committee of Rockefeller Foundation on purchase of land near Walter Reed Memorial Hospital to be presented to U. S. War Department for expansion of the hospital. Letters concerning budgets for serum production and RIMR. Report of Oxford Committee for administering grants from Rockefeller Foundation to assist Belgian professors in England, 1918. Report from James F. Ballard on purchase of scientific books for Peking Union Medical College. Report of the reasons for Rockefeller Foundation's decision not to build a medical school at Shanghai, 1920. Letter from SF on Executive Committee's decision to fund work on animal nutrition by Dr. H. P. Armsby at Pennsylvania State College, 4/19/20. General correspondence on Van Slyke's proposed nutrition study in Germany, 1921. Declaration from Pasteur Institut on its financial needs. Letters between Embree and SF on Rockefeller Foundation's support of Pasteur Institut with 025,000 in 1921, and in subsequent years, 1922-1925. Report of President Vincent and Richard M. Pearce on Canadian medical centers, 1920. Copy of a letter from Embree to Prof. Kritschewsky, of Bacteriological Institute, Moscow, on future policy of Rockefeller Foundation towards funding Russian research. Letters to SF on Rockefeller Foundation's interest in funding studies in the field of human biology, including Raymond Pearl's work on life-span and Robert M. Yerkes' work on animal behavior. SF responds that he had doubts about such a policy and cannot support Foundation's plans to fund a breeding center for anthropoid apes needed for Pearl's and Yerkes' work, 1928. Notice of Embree's leaving Rockefeller Foundation to become chairman of Rosenwald Fund in Chicago. Correspondence about Rosenwald Fund's contribution to Emil Abderhalden, 1930.
  - Emerson, Charles P.
  - Emerson, Ella May
  - Emerson, George H
  - Emerson, Haven, 1912-1934; 5 folders
    Includes: Correspondence on production and distribution of antimeningitis serum. SF strongly opposes distribution of serum without added preservatives. Letters on meningitis carriers in New Yorki and about poliomyelitis in New York City, 1916. Correspondence about work of Alvah Doty for New York City Department of Health. Manuscript on the "Origin and Organization of the American Epidemiological Society," 1927.
  - Emerson, James A.
  - Emerson, Kendall
  - Emery, S. A
  - Emmot, Susan E.
  - Emrys-Roberts, E.
  - Encephalitis lethargica
  - Encyclopedia Britannica
  - Enders, John F.
  - Endicott, A. L.
  - Enelow, H. G.
  - Engel, Paul H.
  - Engel, William
  - Engelhard, George H.
  - English, David C.
  - Enlows, H. F.
  - Enoch, Dr.
  - Ensminger, S. H.
  - Ensor, C. B.
  - Epstein, Albert A.
  - Epstein, Meyer
  - Epstein, Moses
  - Equitable Life Assurance Society of the U.S.A.
  - Erb, I. H.
  - Erben, Franz
  - Erdman, H. B.
  - Erdmann, John F
  - Erdmann, Rhoda, 3 folders
  - Erdwurm, Frank
  - Erlanger, Joseph, 1927; 1944; 6 items; 1 item
    Includes: Correspondence concerning Rockefeller Foundation travelling fellowships. SF suggests eligible students. Congratulations on Erlanger's receipt of Nobel Prize.
  - Ernst, Harold C., 1913-1921; ca. 25 items
    Includes: Correspondence about American Association of Pathologists and Bacteriologists, and suggestions for membership. Request to SF for antimeningitis serum and for rabbits infected with Treonema palladium for research.
  - Ernst, Morris L.
  - Ertischek, Rudolph
  - Eshner, Augustus A.
  - Esmond, Burton D.
  - Esperson, G. E.
  - Espinosa, Arsenio
  - Esteve, Antonio
  - Estey, Mrs. R. N.
  - Estopinal, Leonidas B.
  - Etablissement Leune, Paris
  - Etheridge, Paul S.
  - Ettelson, Lee E.
  - Ettelson, M.
  - Eugenics Research Assoc.
  - Europe
    - Europe, 1912
    - Europe, 1912: Misc.
    - Europe, 1918: American Red Cross, Paris.
    - Europe, 1918: Misc.
    - Europe, 1918: U.S. Army
    - Europe, 1920
    - Europe, 1920: Misc.
  - Europe and Egypt, 1925